WOSSENU FISSEHA

Web Designer / Developer and QA Professional

(201

Phone (301) 500-5993

Email wossenufisseha@gmail.com

Website
WFissehaPortfolio

PROFILE



Experienced Quality Control Professional with a demonstrated history of working in the non-profit organization management industry. Skilled in Federal Contracts, Information Technology, Staff Development, Report Writing, and Strategic Planning.

Knowledge and experience in web and digital design, digital Illustration using Adobe Creative Cloud applications, Motion Graphics, Microsoft Applications, and Integrated Workplace Management System software pro-grams such as Maximo, IBM Cognos Analytics, Actuate and Crystal Reports.

EXPERIENCE

QUALITY CONTROL MANAGER

DoD Contractor - Facilities Management / 2012 - Present

- Implemented, directed, and coordinated the quality assurance program and quality control activities of assigned site contract.
- Ensured the inspection and verification of completed contracted work that meets the contractual requirements
 and established standards through personal performance and direction of subordinates.
- Prepared contract required deliverables, primarily the Quality Control Plan and other documents assigned such as Sustainability Plan and Site Safety Plans.
- Assessed product and equipment capabilities and specifications to establish service delivery standards and proposed quality expectancy of completed work.
- Prepared and completed assigned reporting duties by internal and contractual requirement as well as administration of the inspection and reporting database that will be used on the contract site.

QUALITY CONTROL COORDINATOR

DoD Contractor - Facilities Management / 2011 - 2012

- · Monitored, inspected and evaluated completed work to ensure service process meets contract standards.
- Created reports of quality control inspections and analyzed data to determine if any changes in the service process are necessary. Developed and implemented quality improvement activities and policies.
- Coordinated activities of workers engaged in inspecting and evaluating services in order to control quality of services and to ensure compliance with standard operating procedure and contract requirement

WOSSENU FISSEHA

Web Designer/ Developer and QA Professional

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

QUALITY CONTROL INSPECTOR

DoD Contractor - Facilities Management / 2006 - 2011

- Implemented quality control procedures to ensure compliance with contract specifications and applicable regulations. Inspected all phases of a variety of services and operation for conformity to establish quality, health and safety and other operational standards by performing on-going work for compliance with contractual provisions.
- Ensured all services listed on the performance requirement summary are performed in a satisfactory level.
- Identified/specified areas to be inspected (scheduled and unscheduled) and how and how often inspections will be accomplished. Communicated deficiencies to proper persons. Maintained quality control files and documented results of all inspections

SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- XML/XHML
- Responsive Web Design
- Web Hosting
- UI / UX Design
- User Research
- Wireframing / Storyboarding
- Adobe Creative Suite applications: Ps, Ai, Id, Dw, An, Ae, Xd
- Microsoft Applications
- IBM Maximo
- IBM Cognos Analytics
- SAP Crystal Reports
- Actuate Reports (BIRT)

EDUCATION

B.S. DIGITAL MEDIA AND WEB TECHNOLOGY

University of Maryland Global Campus / Maryland/ USA / 2023

ELECTRONIC IMAGING PREPRESS

Montgomery College / Maryland / USA / 2012

MCDST & MCITP

Graduate School USA / Washington D.C. / USA / 2009